

Nick Rossolatos

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PROFILE

24-year old full stackdeveloper from Greece with3+ years of work experiencein web development.

CONTACT

+30 6976703479 nickrossolatos@gmail.com

 SKILLS	
HTML/(S)CSS	
Javascript	

Nodejs/MongoDB

Responsive design

Testing

OVERVIEW

I specialize in Frontend web development with a focus on clean and efficient Javascript and (S)CSS code. Building working prototypes and MVP's quickly and rolling them out in the market for testing and feedback has been one of my strongest points so far. My background as a startup co-founder, also gives me enough understanding of how a company works and its risks.

SKILLS/EXPERTISE

Мe

- Curious about anything and everything, eager to learn and a quick study
- · Self-starter
- Team player
- Dedicated to providing high quality work with a lot of attention to details
- Knowledge about various computer technology topics, be it hardware, software, networks etc.
- Some business experience, belonging in a startup for more than 2 years

Web Technologies

- Very good HTML,CSS, JavaScript knowledge
- Excellent UI and Javascript debugging and reverse engineering
- · Able to do design & UX research, wireframes, mockups and MVP's
- Junior Illustrator/Photoshop user
- ES6/ES7 Javascript code experience
- Hands on experience with Ember, Angular, React and Aurelia frameworks
- Good NodeJS/MongoDB knowledge
- WebSockets / Server Sent Events experience

Other

- Git
- Cross browser compatibility
- Testing (Tape has been the testing library of choice)
- Process Automation using npm and/or gulp
- Unix knowledge
- Web design and Logo Branding

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Applied Science (B.A.Sc.)@TEI Stereas Elladas September 2009 - June 2015

Solid understanding of basic computer science principles. Proficient with human computer interaction, programming and data mining. My thesis was a recommender system algorithm using collaborative filtering.



Nick Rossolatos

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

	DESIGN	
_	UI/UX	
	Web Design	
	Logo/Branding	

SOCIAL

"You can find me everywhere"



s p i d e y n r



nickrossolatos



nikosrossolatos

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelancer - Frontend Developer September 2015 - Present

Working as a freelancer i have been developing and redesigning the UI in Web Applications using Aurelia/React. I transformed .PSD/.AI files to working code and supported/upgraded the infastructure of existing apps.

CTO/Co-founder @ Panelsensor Ltd

My responsibilities as a CTO @ Panelsensor, include from managing the developers team and taking critical decisions regarding the application, to building the server infastructure, coding and designing new features.

Lead Developer @ Speakerzen.me

October 2013 - June 2014

After winning the Google Launchpad Athens award, i continued developing the app on the full stack and took responsibilities as a lead developer.

Eventually we stopped developing the application since the startup didn't have the required growth. We did although learn a lot from this "failure".

Web developer @ Panagiotis Tzellos Individual Company April 2013 - September 2013

I did my internship at Panagiotis Tzellos Company, where i had the task of building multiple application prototypes and testing them on the market to see how they go. It was my first contact with the startup community and i have been a member since then. I used HTML5/CSS3,JS,Phonegap.

IT support @ TEI of Stereas Elladas

January 2012 - December 2012

My main role @ Tei of Stereas Elladas was to maintain the servers and computers across the institution. I learned to handle linux systems at a production state, which was helpful for my later positions where i needed to create such infastructures alone from scratch. I also learnt to use pfSense servers for security purposes and a Windows active directory.

SPEAKING LANGUAGES

GREEK

NATIVE LANGUAGE

 ${\sf ENGLISH}$

SECOND LANGUAGE